JATIN

P: 437-221-1560 | sainijatin247@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/jatin-s

PROFILE SUMMARY

Electronics Technician with a CGPA of 3.8 having more than three years experience in automotive maintenance industry
Currently working with Chalmers Suspension International Inc. as a Maintenance Technician in Canada, prior to that worked as a Maintenance Engineer with the team of Honda Cars India Ltd.
Member of Cases over coffee focused on refining interpersonal and work management skills.
Flexibility to adapt in different work environment and ability to build trust amongst colleagues.
Dedicated and highly motivated professional with experience in designing, troubleshooting, repair and inspecting complex automation projects and process control operations.

NOTABLE ATTAINMENTS

- PLC programming (Siemens, Mitsubishi, ABB), VFD, HMI designing and simulation.
- Simatic Step 7, RSlinx, RSlogix, GX developer, Automation Studio, Microsoft Visual, AutoCAD.
- Hands on experience on FANUC and KUKA robots, pneumatic and hydraulic components, electronic instruments like Oscilloscope, Function generator, Multimeters, AC/DC power supply.
- Proficient in troubleshooting techniques like fish bone diagram, gantt chart and process bottleneck analysis.
- Analog and digital circuits, LabView, I/O signal, sensor operations, transducers, electrical design, layout and testing.
- Achieved an "A" grade for project presentation & work done in an internship at Global SPS ltd., Mohali, India.

EXPERIENCE

Chalmers Suspension International Inc., Mississauga, ON, Canada

Oct 2020 - Present

- Detect and troubleshoot irregularities and malfunctions, routine maintenance work on machinery.
- Repairing welding equipment, tool grinders and pumps.
- Programming and operating Trumpf Trumatic CNC with TOP200 software.
- Hands-on experience on conventional machines like drilling, lathe, milling, power-saw.

Honda Cars India Limited (HCIL), India Maintenance Engineer in Power-train dept.

Aug 2016 - Mar 2018

- Working experience on Fanuc CNC, Robot, Mitsubishi PLC based machines in Power train section.
- Inspect, repair and installing Fanuc servo, spindle motors, drives and Amplifiers.
- Making breakdown reports, analysis data for individual production lines and improving MTTR and MTBF.
- Machine critical parts identification, indenting, understanding mechanical and electrical drawings.
- Providing Kaizens and frequent improvements on machine line to increase efficiency and production rate.
- · Manpower handling, taking initiatives to make efficient use of allotted resources.
- Working together with production dept. to eliminate troubles and maintain streamlined production.

INTERNSHIP& PROJECTS

Global SPS, Mohali, India Project Trainee

Jul 2015-Aug 2015

- Made a versatile machine named 'Inspection Rig' which can be used to inspect wide range of jobs/products.
- R&D, analyze, inspect, test, debug various sections of the project and successfully executed its operation as per demand.

Arduino UNO Projects Oct 2015-Feb 2016

- Made a bluetooth operated extension board (iBoard) using Arduino uno and controlled it using mobile application.
- Successfully completed Line follower and light curtain projects using Arduino board.

EDUCATION

2018-2020: Post- Secondary Diploma in Electronics Engineering Technician from Durham College, Oshawa, ON, Canada.

2012-2016: Advance Diploma in Mechatronics and Industrial Automation (Electronics) from Indo-Swiss Training Centre (CSIO), Chandigarh, India with aggregate 70.8%